We are going to be joining our personal device to Microsoft Intune.
You know, if you are working for a company and you want your company to be able to manage
users, personal device or mobile device, the user, users, you have that ability to be able
to at all register their device to Microsoft Intune themselves without the tolerance of
an IT administrator.
So because without the device, we already started Microsoft Intune, you will not be able
to manage that device or see what the user is doing or be able to push specific company
application to use as a device.
For example, you have people who work as consultants for company that comes with that
personal device.
Definitely you want to be able to manage that device or manage the apps which are being deployed
to that device from your company.
So let me show you that the device actually personal device, if I go to my settings.
From our settings, we need to click, let us wait for this to get started, click system.
And from system, if I click there about and only about, I am going to go to the advanced
system setup and here on that computer name, you can see that it belongs to the work group
and not the domain.
So what we need to do to install this device to your work group is the following.
There is an old method which you can use to install and join the device to Microsoft Intune,
but I will not be showing you that.
I am going to show you the new method and the preferred method to at least join your device
to mount your personal device to Microsoft Intune.
So what we need to do is, we need to open the Microsoft Store and from the Microsoft
Store, what we need to do right now is to at least search for company portal.
Here you can see we have the company portal, so just click on it.
So we need to download the company portal and from the company portal, then you will need
to actually log on with your login credentials which of course you should have the Microsoft
Intune license to be able to register the device to Intune.
So let me just click get and it says I'm sending with the Microsoft and use this on any
computer device, compatible device, we are going to see no text and the download is still
continue.
So by seeing an notification, don't think that you will not be able to actually download
it on your device.
So this one where you can see it has been downloaded and it is pending and then I thought
which it will be installed.
So let's just wait for some seconds for this to get downloaded and get installed.
So after installation of company portal, I'm successful, what we need to do is to launch
the just launch it.
So here you can see it says Microsoft Intune.
So you need to provide an email address that is how the Microsoft Intune license.
So I've been using the following email address, it's not run, then add global for thoughts
on Microsoft.com and then click next.
So we're going to enter a password and then click sign in.
So here I'm going to skip this off for 10 days.
This is this time on to to ask when you remember your account and let just click OK.
So this is the first part of the configuration process.
So hold on why we already started the device which I'm company to come now apply policy.
So this may take some moments, let me just come back again when we need to go to the
next step.
Here we go.
Now you can see it says you have added your account, so actually you now have access
your position apps and say we select just click done.
So here we go.
You can see right now you can see we have a kel global hotel where we don't have any apps
deployed to this device at the moment.
And also if I click device devices, you can see the device has been set up for corporate
use yet since select Mr. Begin, so let us click on that.
And here we go.
It says add corporate account to this device then connect this device to work.
So let me click next.
So I'm going to actually say connect.
Let's connect our device to see most connected device to your work and then we need to
start a little bit log on again to this device to totally prove our authentication.
Here we go.
You can see that set of device for Nora, so let me just click next.
Say we are taking you to your organization signing page so that we need to resign in again.
So now let's enter the password for Nora.
I'm just enter the password and then click signing.
So I'm going to skip this for 14 days.
Here we go.
Let me just say yes for that.
You can see hold on.
I will resize the device to company up, apply policy.
So it says you to take a few minutes to connect to your school or workplace and the company
apps, network settings, email accounts with policies and others.
So let's just click Got It.
And I take it.
You can see right now when I have your device, it's not connected to work.
So let's select Next.
So we say it's trying to check the device.
That was on here.
You can see it's not connected.
We are now done.
So that's when you can see we don't have these devices Nora.
So I'm going to assess company's resources, so if I go back again to, let me go back
to Azure Active Directory.
If I go to Azure Active Directory and I go to my let's say devices and I go to all devices.
So right now that the device should be actually here, you can see we have the device
as a PD with the device with Nora just joined and it's totally an Azure AD registered.
And it's not at all an hybrid Azure AD joined.
So right now you can see the difference and the MDM is actually Microsoft Intune and it's
a compliance.
You can see, yes.
So all of the devices have not been joined to Intune, but already they are only hybrid
Azure AD joined, but they have not been joined to Intune and compared to just these devices.
Azure AD with means that is actually getting connection directly to the Azure AD and not
to my domain baroments.
So what you can now do is let's go to Microsoft Intune and at this moment, it would take
some time for that device to appear here in Intune.
So you can see all devices, but at this moment, we've not started seeing the device in
Intune, it takes some minutes for the device to appear in Intune.
So what I just did is I tried to do a sync from my first null device that's the PD01.
Then if I go back again to Intune and I do a refresh and then you cannot see how the
device is at all being displayed with the PD01 and the first null device here, you can
see it does not the best null device if it's owned by a company, you can see a corporate
and a compliance, you can see the compliance and it's a Windows device version.
And you can see that I will be familiar with the device at all in our facilities using
this Intune account.
So next I will show you how to totally join hybrid devices to also Microsoft Intune.
Bye.